a Contracting party is generally free to
assign all or part of their rights under
a contract to somebody else
but what is required to ensure that this
assignment is valid
the Virginia Supreme Court considered
this question in Kelly Healthcare versus
the Prudential Insurance Company of
America
William green and his wife Joan green
were insured under a health insurance
policy issued by the Prudential
Insurance Company of America
Joan Greene received medical services
from Kelly Healthcare
before receiving care from Kelly Green
signed two documents the first document
stated that green understood that
insurance proceeds from Prudential may
be paid directly to Kelly
the second document stated that green
authorized direct payments from
Prudential to Kelly
Prudential never received the first
document and only received the second
several months after Kelly began
providing services to Green
Kelly submitted Green's Health Care
bills to Prudential but Prudential
refused to pay benefits directly to
Kelly
filed suit against Green and Prudential
Kelly argued that it was Green's
assignee under the health insurance
policy and in the alternative that it
was a third party beneficiary under the
policy
the trial court granted a default
judgment against Greene
Prudential moved for summary judgment
the trial court granted the motion
finding that the documents between Kelly
and green were an authorization not an
assignment Kelly appealed to the
Virginia Supreme Court